How's it going everyone? This is going
to be a trade review over a scalp I took
on ES. We're going to talk about
relative strength and weakness. Why I
chose ES as the middle asset as well as
the setup for it and the time frame
pairings for scalping. You can see here
we have equal highs at the highs which
is the draw on liquidity for me on this
trade and why I was looking to scalp it.
But the main reason is the previous day
low SMT. So taking a look at this we
have YM here ES here MQ here. What is
the weakest asset? And there's a few
things I look at this right where is the
location of price currently relative to
structure the SMT as well as just
candles. So you can see here NQ is the
closest to its previous day low. So that
shows me it has weakness. If I look at
the candle type, you can see YM has a
nice bullish candle while NQ does not
have a bullish candle, right? It is a
bullish candle, but it's not quite
bullish. It's not expansion, right? It's
a reversal candle. Now, also looking at
SMT, what do I notice? Well, we notice
that ENQ is below this low, while ES and
YM are not. So, taking a look at this
and comparing all three, it tells me
that NQ is the weakest asset and YM is
the strongest asset. So, generally
speaking, if I want to take a long
setup, I'm going to be looking for YM
and a short setup, I'd be looking for
NQ. Now, going to the 15-minute chart,
as this is what I was watching on it,
right? I want to wait for open because
for me, there's no way to trade NQ here
with all these failure swings on the
high. So, I can't frame short off the
open unless I'm going to wait for a
manipulation and then trade into the
low. So, letting this play out, you can
see we do get that manipulation, trade
into the low, and then we have a
reversal closure after taking out our
previous day low. So, taking a look at
this, if NQ is going to reverse off of
its previous day low, then I'd be
looking to long the stronger assets,
right? And the reason for this is the
structure. You can see all the failure
swings lined up here on the highs. That
is what I was looking for as well as
these equal highs on ES. Now, what are
the few things that I can look for here?
Well, do I want to take a look at the
strongest asset? Yes. Would I want to
trade the strongest asset? No, because
it has already expanded and it's over
highs. So, this is where if I'm going to
want to trade, I want to see that YN
does not reverse here and trade lower.
and Q does reverse here and trade higher
and then I can look to take the middle
asset because that's the next strongest
asset. This is very similar to the last
trade review I posted on ES as I am
trading the middle asset because the
other one I'm expecting some
consolidation.
So let's go ahead and zoom into ES here
with that context and we'll go ahead and
clean it up and mark it up. So
essentially the context is we have that
previous day low SMT as well as the SMT
here and then looking at the lower time
frame here we have a nice candle 2
closure and a candle 3 continuation. Now
why am I letting this candle 3 close?
Well, I'm letting NQ close its candle
here. So letting NQ show that we have a
reversal means that I need to let ES
also have a reversal here. So let's take
a look here at the lower time frames.
we'll drop down to the 1 minute time
frame. So down here on the 1 minute time
frame, I've also added the hourly time
frame along with the 15minute. So you
can see we have a 15-minute candle to
closure. We have that change in the
state of delivery and we have also
formed a continuation. Now with this,
why am I showing the hourly time frame?
Well, because if I'm going to trade the
15-minut and 1 minute time frame, I want
to align that also with a higher time
frame. And this 1-hour candle has a
small wick reversing off of its previous
hour, which supports expansion higher.
So now I know I want to be looking for a
trade higher in the next 15-minute
candle. So I look in here. Do I have any
low that I consider to be protected? No,
I only have this one. So am I going to
take a position here with my stop all
the way down here and looking for this
target? No, I'm not going to. I'm going
to let a new low form.
Well, in this case, NQ, if we zoom out,
you can see ENQ has taken this low here
while ES has not. That is forming SMT.
And so then now I can look for this
series of down close candles here as an
opposing candle if it is closed back
over. So, zooming back in, let's see if
we get the closure over that.
We do. And so then with that, I'm
looking to take a position. I want to be
in before these failure swings are taken
and target those highs. Now, in this
case, I was in right around here. I had
my stop pretty tight below the bodies
and then I was looking for these highs.
Now, I didn't execute on the closure
because I was actually logging into my
broker. So, I got a better fill than
that, which was right around here and
when we got in and then we start to
trade away and then this is a new
continuation right here. So with this, I
went ahead. I had my entry there. I took
some off at 2 R. And then I was holding
for these highs. I took a little bit
more off at these highs right here when
we took them out. And then I had the
majority of my position left to reach
for this high here. Now, when we go up
and touch this high, I actually did not
get filled on my limit. So I was not
waiting for price to hit this. I just
went ahead and exited because I'm not
going to give up most of my position for
a tick or two. So exiting that, I just
have runners left. I then watch price
trade into here. I'm currently sitting
at break even with my stop loss. Price
sweeps out a low and then do we close
over this level? We do. So then I move
my stop to right here. That is a new
protected swing. So, I was looking for
price to continue higher here without
taking out this low. Price returns to
this low and then stops me out right
there. So, that was my position there.
So, quickly to review, we'll go back top
down going to the hourly chart here. We
have SMT with NQ off the previous day's
low. And we also have SMT right here as
NQ ran it out and ES did not. The hourly
candle here supports expansion as it is
a reversal candle and it has context and
a small wick. I then drop down to the
15minut time frame. On the 15minut time
frame here we had a candle to closure.
And then why did I let candle 3 close?
Because I was using NQ. So if we go to
NQ here, that 9:30 candle, I was letting
that close, which is this same candle
here. And then I'm looking to trade this
candle for continuation higher. So going
down to the 1 minute time frame, I'm
looking in here for my entry. I have an
SMT as NQ has taken out that low. I have
a continuation order block here. And
then I look to take my position and I
partial off at logical points over 2 R.
And then at my target, I get knocked out
of my runners here. And what happens
eventually? Well, we come back down
here. We still respect that protected
swing. and then we eventually go and run
higher here. So, that is the full
breakdown of my scalp and trade review.
If you want to see more of these, let me
know in the comments section below. But
if I'm going to be looking to scalp, I'm
going to use the hourly time frame for
context or my bias or a candle that
supports expansion and then using the
15-minute as a swing point and 1 minute
as entry. So, a 15-minute and 1 minute
fractal model. This is very similar to
using a daily for bias, a 4-hour candle
closure, and a 15-minute for entry. With
that, I hope you have a great rest of
your day and I'll see you guys next
time. Have a good one.